Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Corporate Anniversaries, 1945-2014 and undated RL.11170
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Corporate Anniversaries
1945-2015 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11170
5.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Collection contains clippings, correspondence, published commemorations, videotapes, memorabilia and other materials produced or collected relating to key JWT anniversaries. Includes materials relating to anniversaries of the JWT London Office and also JWT's client relationship with Unilever. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising and Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, original audiovisual materials are closed until use copies can be produced. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Corporate Anniversaries were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987-2015. Collection was assembled initially by JWT Archives staff and later Hartman Center staff from materials originally present in other JWT collections in order to facilitate routine reference inquiries.
Collection Overview
Contains clippings, correspondence, published commemorations, videotapes, memorabilia and other materials produced or collected relating to key JWT anniversaries. Includes materials relating to anniversaries of the JWT London Office and also JWT's client relationship with Unilever. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising and Marketing History.
Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- General Files, 1945-2002; 1
  - 125th anniversary lapel pin, 1989 (Box 1)
  - 1945 Credentials Book (Box 1)
  - Campaign, 100 Years of JWT and Unilever 1902-2002 (Box 7)
  - Fortune profile, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Fortune profile, 1947 (Box 7)
  - London Office: JWT at 70--What Next?, 1996 (Box 7)
  - London Office: Times Supplement, 1962 (Box 7)
- 100th Anniversary, 1963-1965; 2
  - Acknowledgements, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Advertising Age, 1964; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1965; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Historical advertisements, undated (Box 2)
  - Letters, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Materials for anniversary celebration, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Office chronologies, undated (Box 2)
  - RL-11170-3/4-001. 100 Years of Making Ads and Making History. Umatic., 1991 (Box 3)
  - RL-11170-3/4-002. 100th Anniversary Celebration Part 1 of 2. Umatic, 1991 (Box 3)
  - RL-11170-3/4-003. 100th Anniversary Celebration Part 2 of 2. Umatic, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Advertising Age feature issue (multiple copies), 1964 (Box 4)
- 125th Anniversary, 1989; 3
  - Advertising Age, JWT at 125, 1989 (Box 7)
  - Advertising Leadership 1864-1989 (Box 1)
  - Advertising Leadership 1864-1989 (Box 7)
  - Backstage Spotlight, 1989 (Box 7)
  - Marketing Magazine: JWT 125th Supplement, 1989 (Box 7)
- 150th Anniversary, 2013-2014; 4
  - 150th anniversary website correspondence, 2014 (Box 5)
  - Advertising Age, 2014 (Box 5)
  - Binder: Assets received from Duke University Archives, 2013 (Box 5)
  - CBS Sunday Morning talking points, 2014 (Box 5)
  - J. Walter Thompson Company 150 Years (multiple copies), 2014 (Box 5)
  - Lions Daily News (multiple copies), 2014 (Box 5)
  - Various artifacts: notebooks, mug, pin, 2014 (Box 5)
  - Banners, circa 2014 (Box 6)